J. Robert Oppenheimer Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Government File, 1942-1954 (Box 171-196)
  - Atomic Energy Commission General Advisory Committee
    - Radioisotopes, 1947
    - Reactors for research, 1947
    - Report to president, 1947-1952, (2 folders)
    - Schedules for meetings, 1947
    - Subcommittees, 1950
    - Travel, 1948-1949
  - Atomic explosions, 1950 (Box 177)
  - Atomic weapons handbook, 1949
  - Bevatron, proposal of the University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill., 1948
  - Biological warfare, Oppenheimer's note on, Undated
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, Upton, N.Y., 1947-1952, (4 folders)
  - California Radiation Laboratory, Berkeley, Calif., 1949-1950 (Box 178)
  - California, University of, Berkeley, Calif., budget, 1947-1948
  - Certificates of destruction, 1946-1952
  - Civil defense, 1950
  - Classification grades, 1949
  - Clearance procedures, 1948-1954
  - Clearance reports, 1947-1954
  - Colby, Walter F., correspondence
    - General, 1948-1953
    - Kluych, Alex R., 1949
  - Communist organizations, attorney general's list, 1950-1954
  - Criteria for determining eligibility for personnel, 1948
  - Crossroads, Joint Chiefs of Staff Evaluation Board, 1945-1953
  - Dupont survey, 1949
  - Eniwetok tests, 1947-1952
  - General receipts (Box 179)
    - Incoming, 1945-1954, (9 folders)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943-1955, (5 folders) (Box 180)
    - Outgoing, 1946-1954, (9 folders)
  - Hartwell report, 1950 (Box 181)
  - Harwell Declassification Conference, Harwell, England, 1948-1949
  - Interdepartmental Science Committee, 1949-1953
  - Isotopes, 1947-1949
  - Joint Congressional Committee on Atomic Energy, 1947-1949
  - Joint Research and Development Board, 1946-1947
  - Los Alamos Laboratory, Los Alamos, N.Mex. (Box 182)
    - Accounting for documents, 1946-1950
    - Addenda, 1949
    - Challenger, Helen F., 1949-1951
    - Correction notices, 1947-1952
    - Correspondence, 1942-1946
    - Declassified documents, 1947-1948
    - Downgrading notices, 1947-1952, (7 folders)
    - Errata, 1949
    - History, 1945-1947, 1961 (Box 183)
    - Inventory of documents, 1945-1949, (2 folders)
    - Investigation of property accounts, 1947
    - Receipts, 1946-1952, (2 folders); (7 folders) (Box 184)
    - Reports, 1952
    - Upgrading, 1950
  - Military Liaison Committee, 1948-1952
  - Military Operations Subcommittee, 1954
  - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1945-1949
  - National Defense Research Committee, 1944
  - National Science Foundation, 1948-1952, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 185)
  - Naval Research Advisory Committee, 1946-1965, (9 folders)
  - Navy Department, 1948-1951
  - Neutron-proton scattering, Undated (Box 186)
  - New Kittigazuit Group, 1952-1953, (2 folders)
  - Nuclear Advisory Committee, 1946
  - Nuclear Science Abstracts, 1950-1953
  - Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Studies, Oak Ridge, Tenn., 1946-1947
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tenn., 1947-1952, (3 folders)
  - Office of Science Research and Development, 1943-1946, (2 folders)
  - Personnel security policy and criteria, 1948-1950
  - Personnel security questionnaires, 1951-1953
  - Photographs, atomic bomb, 1951, 1965
  - Project East River, 1951-1952, undated, (3 folders); (8 folders) (Box 187)
  - Project Lincoln, 1952
  - Project Vista, 1951
  - Radioactive waste material, 1949
  - Reactor science and technology, 1951-1953
  - Registered mail, 1951
  - Research and Development Board, Committee on Atomic Energy
    - 10-7 Panel, 1949-1952
    - Ad hoc panel on long-range objectives, 1948-1951
    - Ad hoc panel on technical estimates, 1950
    - Agenda, 1947-1952
    - Appointment of Oppenheimer, 1947-1950
    - Base Surge Panel, 1949-1953
    - Directives, 1947-1953
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., visit, 1951
    - Inventory of documents, 1951-1954 (Box 188)
    - Members, 1947-1953
    - Memoranda, 1947-1953, (2 folders)
    - Minutes, 1947-1948
    - Press releases, 1953
    - Radiological Instrument Panel, 1947
    - Receipts
      - Incoming, 1947-1953, (7 folders)
      - Outgoing, 1948-1953
    - Starks, J. C., correspondence, 1953 (Box 189)
    - Travel, 1948-1953
  - Rutgers, A. G., 1950
  - Science Advisory Committee, Office of Defense Mobilization
    - Chairman's reports, 1952
    - East River project, 1952
    - Exchange of technical information, 1951
    - German science, 1949-1951
    - Membership, Undated
    - Memoranda, 1951-1953
    - Minutes, 1951-1952
    - National Defense Award, 1952
    - National Science Foundation, 1951-1952
    - Oppenheimer appointment, 1950-1954
    - Personnel, 1951-1952
    - President's report, 1952
    - Press releases, 1951-1952
    - Princeton, N.J., meeting, 1952-1953
    - Reorganization, 1952-1953
    - Research and development program, 1951-1952
    - Scientists and mobilization, 1951-1953 (Box 190)
    - Systems engineering, 1947-1953
    - Washington, D.C., meeting, 1953
  - Scientific panel, War Department, 1945
  - Secrecy, 1948
  - Security
    - Acknowledgments, Undated
    - Checks, 1948-1953
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1954
    - Regulations, 1947-1951
    - Termination statements, 1947
  - Senate Military Affairs Committee, 1945-1950
  - State Department (Box 191)
    - Atomic policy broadcasts to Russia, 1947
    - Board of consultants, 1946, (3 folders)
    - Disarmament Panel
      - Articles on disarmament, 1952-1953, undated See also Classified
      - Bundy, McGeorge, 1952-1953
      - Clearance of members, 1952
      - General correspondence, 1952-1953
      - Memoranda, 1952
      - Miscellaneous, 1948-1953
      - Oppenheimer appointment, 1952
      - Press and publicity, 1952-1953
      - Princeton, N.J., meeting, 1947-1952
    - Policy planning staff, 1948 (Box 192)
    - Policy survey group, 1950
    - Working committee, 1945
  - Strategic air warfare, 1951
  - Top secret
    - Accounting for documents, 1948-1952
    - Authentication of documents, 1947-1952, (3 folders)
    - Control, 1949-1951 (Box 193)
    - Downgrading notices, 1948-1953
    - Inventory, 1948-1952
    - Monthly reports, 1948-1949
    - Receipts, 1945-1952, (6 folders)
    - Reproduction of documents, 1947
    - Transfer of documents, 1948
    - Transmittal of documents, 1950
  - Transfer and accountability station, 1951 (Box 194)
  - Transmittals, 1947-1953, (3 folders)
  - Travel, 1950
  - United Nations Atomic Energy Commission
    - Bibliography, 1949
    - Clearance for Oppenheimer, 1947
    - General correspondence, 1945-1947, undated, (5 folders) (Box 195)
    - Printed matter, 1945-1952, (2 folders)
    - Resolutions, 1949
    - Review of Fear, War and the Bomb, by P. M. S. Blackett, 1947-1949
    - Russian broadcast, 1948
    - Translation of Russian article, 1946
    - Transmission of Information, 1946
  - Vault, 1945-1955, (5 folders) (Box 196)
  - War Department, Interim Committee on Atomic Energy, 1945-1946
  - Washington, D.C.
    - Office, 1952
    - Press seminars, 1949
    - Reservations, 1952-1953
  - Weather Bureau, 1953
- Security Case File, 1953-1967 (Box 197-225)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, drafts, notes, press releases, clippings, and printed matter relating to security hearings.
  - Atomic Energy Commission case (Box 197)
    - Classified file, 1953-1954 See also Classified
    - Findings and recommendations, 1954, (2 folders)
    - Letter of charges, 1953-1955, (2 folders)
    - Rolander, C. A., Jr., reply to article “We Accuse!” by Joseph Alsop and Stewart Alsop in Harper's Magazine, 1954 (Box 198)
  - Autograph and photograph request, 1945-1954
  - Biography, 1954, undated, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 199)
  - Biography/bibliography, 1954
  - Case Institute of Technology, Cleveland, Ohio, invitation, 1954 (Box 200)
  - Chevalier, Haakon, 1954-1966, (2 folders)
  - Classified file, other than Atomic Energy Commission, 1953-1955
  - Crouch, Paul, 1954
  - Ecker, Allen, 1954
  - Gardner, Trevor, 1954
  - Garrison, Lloyd K.
    - Briefs, 1954, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 201)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955
    - Summation, 1953-1954
  - Hinton, William and Joan, 1954
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1954
  - Institute for Advanced Study, 1947, 1954, (2 folders)
  - Jungk, Robert, book, 1958-1963
  - Lawyers, 1954 (Box 202)
  - Letters
    - Friends, 1954
    - Friends and special interest, 1942-1956 See also Classified
    - General (Box 203)
      - “A-H” miscellaneous, 1954-1955, (6 folders)
      - “I-Z” miscellaneous, 1954-1955, (8 folders) (Box 204)
    - Re case, 1957-1962, (5 folders) (Box 205)
  - Linn, Edward, 1957
  - Marks, Herbert S., 1952-1954
  - Notes and memoranda on hearings, Undated
  - Oppenheimer (Robert) Fund, 1954, (3 folders)
  - Passport, 1954-1955
  - Paynter, Henry, 1954-1959
  - Play, The Oppenheimer Case (Box 206)
    - Belgian version, 1964-1965, (2 folders)
    - French version, 1964-1965, (2 folders) (Box 207)
    - German version, 1964-1966, (4 folders)
    - London and New York productions, 1965-1966
    - Other productions, 1964-1966
    - U.S. version, 1966
  - Press (Box 208)
    - Clippings, 1953-1966, undated, (7 folders); (5 folders); (4 folders); (8 folders) (Box 209, Box 210, Box 211, Box 212, Box 213, Box 214, Box 215, Box 216)
    - Inquiries, 1954-1955 (Box 217)
    - Institute board of trustees, 1954
    - Invitations to speak, 1954
    - Letters of support, 1954
    - Miscellaneous, 1954, (2 folders)
    - Statements, 1954, (2 folders)
    - Washington, University of, Seattle, Wash., 1954-1955
  - Pyramid Club, Philadelphia, Pa., 1960
  - Robert Oppenheimer Fund See Container 205, Oppenheimer (Robert) Fund
  - Special articles, book reviews, etc., re Oppenheimer case (Box 218)
    - Alsop, Joseph and Stewart, We Accuse!, 1954-1955
    - Brown, John Mason, Through These Men, 1954-1957
    - Curtis, Charles P., The Oppenheimer Case, 1955
    - Egger, David, “An Open Mind”, in Sequoia, 1958
    - Shepley, James, and Clay Blair, The Hydrogen Bomb, 1954
    - Thomas, Morgan, Atomic Energy and Congress, 1956
    - Wharton, Michael, A Nation's Security, Undated
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1959
  - Vista and state papers transmitted to the Atomic Energy Commission, 1954
  - Washington, University of, Seattle, Wash., 1953-1955
  - Transcript of hearings before the Personnel Security Board, 1954, (2 vols.) (Box 219)
    - Vols. 1-23, 1949 (Box 220)
  - Transcript of hearings with deletions (Box 221)
    - Vols. 1-4, 1954
    - Vols. 5-8, 1954 (Box 222)
    - Vols. 9-13, 1954 (Box 223)
    - Vols. 14-19, 1954 (Box 224)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1954-1955, (2 folders) (Box 225)
- Personal File, 1932-1967 (Box 226-237)
  Letters received and copies of letters sent, awards, honors, bibliographical and biographical material, financial papers, physics papers, and testimonies.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Awards and honors (Box 226)
    - Association of American Scientists, 1965
    - Barbizon Studio of Fashion Modeling, 1950
    - Brazilian Academy of Sciences, 1953-1954
    - Bric-A-Brac, 1964
    - Calcutta University, Calcutta, India, 1957
    - California, University of, Berkeley, Calif., 1948
    - Christ's College, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, England, 1950-1953
    - Cyma Watch Award, 1951-1952
    - Drexel Institute of Technology, Philadelphia, Pa., 1957
    - Enrico Fermi Award See same Container, Fermi (Enrico) Award
    - Father's Day Award, 1950
    - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies Award, 1950
    - Fermi (Enrico) Award, 1961-1964, (5 folders)
    - French Coin Medal, 1966 (Box 227)
    - Golden Slipper Square Club, Philadelphia, Pa., 1959-1960
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1947
    - Japan Academy of Science, 1950, 1962
    - Kessler Institute for Rehabilitation, West Orange, N. J., 1955-1956
    - King's Medal for Service, 1948-1952
    - La Plata University, La Plata, Argentina, 1961
    - Légion d'Honneur, 1957-1958
    - Miscellaneous, 1960-1966
    - New Mexico, University of, Albuquerque, N.M., 1947
    - Oppenheimer School, Levittown, Pa., 1958-1959
    - Oxford University, Oxford, England, 1953
    - Page One Ball, 1955
    - Popular Mechanics Magazine, 1951-1952
    - Princeton University, Princeton, N.J., 1966 (Box 228)
    - Prix des Trois Physiciens, 1958-1966
    - Pyramid Club, Philadelphia, Pa., 1954-1959
    - Roosevelt University, Chicago, Ill., 1955-1956
    - Royal Danish Academy of Sciences and Letters, 1950
    - Royal Society, London, England, 1962
    - Willkie Memorial Building Award, Undated
  - Bibliography, 1961-1967
  - Biography
    - Requests for information, miscellaneous, 1956-1964
    - Age of Science, 1955
    - American Institute of Physics, 1956
    - American Men of Science, 1948-1954
    - American Peoples Encyclopedia, 1948-1955
    - Carster's Diplomatic and Official Guide, Undated
    - Current Biography, 1945, 1964
    - Encyclopædia Britannica, 1961
    - Fieldston-Ethical Alumni Association, 1953 (Box 229)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1951
    - International Who's Who, 1954
    - Jewish Year Book, 1954-1956
    - Leaders in American Science, 1953
    - Listing of memberships, 1962
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-1964
    - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1946-1967
    - Rockefeller Foundation Fellowship, 1950
    - Rowohlts Deutsche Encyklopädie, 1958
    - State Department, 1948
    - Who Knows-and What, 1950-1952
    - Who's Who, (British) 1947-1967
    - Who's Who in America, 1945-1962
    - Who's Who in American Education, 1952-1954
    - Who's Who in Federal Administration, 1948
    - Who's Who in the East, 1954
    - Who's Who in the Western Hemisphere, 1943
    - Who's Who in World Jewry, 1952-1955
    - Who's Who on the Pacific Coast, 1946-1949
    - World Biography, 1948-1952
    - Year, 1950
  - California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, Calif., 1941-1947, (2 folders) (Box 230)
  - California, University of, Berkeley, Calif., 1943-1947
  - Correspondence with secretary
    - 1948-1956, (6 folders)
    - 1957-1966, (12 folders) (Box 231)
  - Files, description of, 1941-1947
  - Financial (Box 232)
    - Bills and receipts, 1943-1946
    - Contracts, 1942-1953
    - Insurance, 1943-1946
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1949
    - Patents, 1943-1953
    - Real estate, 1941-1952
    - Retirement, 1943-1945
    - Travel authorizations, 1942-1953, (3 folders)
  - History of recent physics, 1962-1966
  - Institute for Advanced Study (Box 233)
    - Anniversary dinner, 1955
    - Director, 1947-1966, (4 folders)
    - Earle Conference on German Rearmament, 1950
    - Ford Foundation grant, 1951-1952
    - General, 1957, 1966-1967
    - Interpretation of History Conference, 1949
    - Legal studies, 1950
    - Literary studies, 1948-1951
    - Memoranda, 1951-1955
    - Meteorology Conference, 1958
    - Office supplies, 1952, 1965-1967
    - Physics bibliography, Undated
    - Resignation, 1965-1966
    - Scroll, 1966
  - Miscellany, 1964-1967
  - Papers, disposition of, 1964-1967
  - Physics (Box 234)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1932-1947, 1957, undated, (9 folders)
    - Photographs, Undated, (2 folders)
    - Seminar and colloquium notices, 1947-1967 (Box 235)
  - Relative claims, 1945-1966, (2 folders)
  - Testimony
    - California State Senate Committee on Un-American Activities, 1950, (6 folders)
    - Kilgore-Magnuson bill, 1945-1960, (2 folders)
    - May-Johnson bill, 1945-1946 (Box 236)
    - President's Committee on International Information Activities, 1953
    - U.S. Congress Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, 1949, (3 folders)
    - U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Un-American Activities, 1947-1953, (5 folders)
  - Testimony (Box 237)
    - U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee, Subcommittee on Internal Security, 1951
    - U.S. Special Senate Committee on Atomic Energy (McMahon Committee), 1945-1946, (2 folders)
    - Weinberg, Joseph W., perjury trial, 1941, 1951-1953 See also Container 77, same heading, (12 folders)
- Speech, Lecture, and Writing File, 1926-1966 (Box 238-288)
  - Early Scientific Writings, 1926-1950 (Box 238-240)
    Reprints, galley proofs, and one draft.
    Arranged chronologically with an annotated list.
    - List of writings (Box 238)
    - 1926-1935, (33 folders)
    - 1937-1939, (16 folders) (Box 239)
    - 1940-1950, undated, (10 folders) (Box 240)
  - General Writings, 1939-1966 (Box 241-288)
    Drafts, notes, galley proofs, requests to reprint or quote, correspondence, clippings, printed matter, and an index.
    Arranged alphabetically by title and/or publisher.
    - Index Cards, 1946-1966 (Box 241)
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research, 1962-1963 (Box 242)
    - Alberta, University of, Edmonton, Canada, 1961-1962, (2 folders)
    - Allen, George E., 1951
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1953-1961, (5 folders)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1958-1963, (6 folders)
    - American Institute of Architects, 1959-1966, (5 folders) (Box 243)
    - American Institute of Physics, 1955-1962, undated, (8 folders)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1945-1963, (3 folders) (Box 244)
    - American Physical Society, 1946-1967, (8 folders)
    - American Psychological Association, 1955-1966, (6 folders) (Box 245)
    - Association of Los Alamos Scientists See Container 262, Los Alamos Scientists, Association of
    - Association of Radio News Analysts, 1956
    - Basel, Switzerland, conference. See Container 253, Congress for Cultural Freedom
    - Basic Research Symposium. See Container 287, Weaver's Symposium
    - Bethe, Hans A., festschrift, 1965-1967
    - Bohr, Niels, birthday message, 1955
    - Brazil lectures, 1949-1953, undated, (9 folders) (Box 246)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1959-1966, (5 folders)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory, Upton, N.Y. (Box 247)
      - High energy book, 1964-1965
      - Pegram Lectures, 1962-1965, undated, (5 folders)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1962-1963, (2 folders)
    - California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, Calif., 1948-1964, (6 folders); (5 folders) (Box 248)
    - California, University of, various campuses, 1944-1966, (7 folders)
    - Carlson Lecture See Container 261, Iowa State University
    - Chicago, University of, Chicago, Ill., 1948-1949 (Box 249)
    - Chicago Press, University of, 1960-1961
    - Christian Century, 1962-1963
    - Colorado, University of, Boulder, Colo., 1960-1962, (2 folders)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System
      - Edward R. Murrow show, 1954-1960, (8 folders)
      - General, 1957-1964, (5 folders) (Box 250)
    - Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
      - 1953-1966, (6 folders); (8 folders) (Box 251, Box 252)
    - Committee on the Present Danger, 1951
    - Condon Lectures (University of Oregon), 1949-1962, undated, (5 folders)
    - Conference on Science and the World View, 1956 (Box 253)
    - Conference on Science Information, 1961
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1959-1966, (14 folders)
    - Cooper Union, New York, N.Y., 1947-1948 (Box 254)
    - Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., 1946-1955, (5 folders)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1952-1962, (3 folders); (12 folders) (Box 255)
    - Council on Higher Education in the American Republics, 1963-1964, (2 folders) (Box 256)
    - Daily Princetonian, 1956
    - Danmarks Radio, 1962
    - Dartmouth College, Hanover, N.H., 1958-1960, (2 folders)
    - December, 1963
    - Denver, University of, Denver, Colo., 1946-1952, (2 folders)
    - Drexel Institute of Technology, Philadelphia, Pa., 1956-1957, (2 folders)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1939, 1954, undated, (3 folders)
    - Enciclopedia Tematica Universal, 1966
    - Encyclopædia Britannica, 1957-1959
    - Ethical Culture Schools, New York, N.Y., 1948-1949
    - Federation of American Scientists, 1945-1947 (Box 257)
    - Fermi, Enrico
      - Award, 1963
      - Film, 1954, 1965-1966
      - Memorial edition, 1955
    - Foreign Affairs, 1947-1948, (4 folders)
    - Fortune, 1956-1957
    - Free World magazine, 1946
    - Fulbright Conference on Higher Education, 1957-1959
    - Fund for the Republic, 1963-1964, (5 folders)
    - Galileo, 400th anniversary, 1959-1966 (Box 258)
    - Geneva, University of, Geneva, Switzerland, 1961-1966, (5 folders)
    - George School, Bucks County, Pa., commencement, June 1956
    - Glenco Corporation Discussion Group, 1955
    - Goucher College, Towson, Md., 1955- 1956
    - Hampton Institute, Hampton, Va., 1955-1959, (2 folders)
    - Hara Shobo, proposed publication, 1963
    - Harvard University, James Lectures, Cambridge, Mass., 1947-1948, 1955-1965, undated, (8 folders); (6 folders) (Box 259, Box 260)
    - Haverford College, Haverford, Pa., 1 Nov. 1955
    - Herter Lectures. See Container 262, Johns Hopkins University
    - Hiroshima Diary, 1955-1956
    - Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers/Brevard Engineering College, lecture, 1963-1965
    - Institute of International Education, 1949, 1961, (2 folders)
    - Instituto de Pesquisas da Marinha, 1961
    - Inter-American Defense College talk, 1965
    - International Business Machines Corp., 1953-1954
    - International House, New York, N.Y., 1960 (Box 261)
    - International Press Institute, 1958-1966, (6 folders)
    - Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa, Carlson Lecture, 1954-1967, (5 folders)
    - James Lectures See Container 259, Harvard University, James Lectures, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Japan, visit, 1960-1962, (6 folders)
    - Jeunes-Science, 1958
    - Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md., Herter Lectures, 1948-1949 (Box 262)
    - Kessler Institute for Rehabilitation, West Orange, N.Y., 1956
    - Kissinger, Henry, book, 1957
    - La Tribune de Génevè, 1964
    - Lawrenceville School, Lawrenceville, N.J., 1957-1963, (2 folders)
    - Liberation, 1965
    - Life Magazine, 1954
    - Lilienthal, David E., letter to, 1946, 1960
    - Little Memorial Lecture. See Container 264, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Little Memorial Lecture
    - Look, 1946
    - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, Los Alamos, N.Mex., 1943-1945, 1963-1967, (6 folders)
    - Los Alamos Scientists, Association of, 1945-1947
    - Lowell Institute Cooperative Broadcasting Council, Cambridge, Mass., 1957 (Box 263)
    - March of Time statement, 1948-1950, (2 folders)
    - Maryland Department of Health, 1957
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Amherst, Mass.
      - American Project Conference, 1956-1958, (3 folders)
      - Centennial panel, 1960-1963, (2 folders) (Box 264)
      - Little Memorial Lecture, 1947-1965, (9 folders)
      - Publications, 1957-1959 (Box 265)
    - McMahon, Brien, letter, 1949
    - McMaster University, Hamilton, Canada, Whidden Lecture, 1960-1966, (4 folders)
    - Miami, University of, Coral Gables, Fla., 1964-1965
    - Michigan, University of, Ann Arbor, Mich., 1961-1963, (2 folders)
    - Milton Academy, Milton, Mass., 1964-1965, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1945-1966
    - Monterey Peninsular College, Monterey, Calif., 1958-1962
    - Nassau Club, Princeton, N.J., 1960 (Box 266)
    - Nation, 1956-1957
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1963-1966, (10 folders)
    - National Book Awards, 1962-1964, (7 folders)
    - National Broadcasting Co., White Paper, 1964-1965 (Box 267)
    - National Educational Television and Radio Center, 1962-1963
    - National Policy Committee, 1945-1946
    - National War College, Washington, D.C., 1946-1950, (3 folders)
    - Naval Research Laboratory, Washington, D.C., 1956
    - New Jersey Resolutions for World Government, 1949
    - New York Bar Association, 1947-1951, (5 folders)
    - New York Philharmonic Symphony Program, 1945-1960 (Box 268)
    - New York Philosophy Club, New York, N.Y., 1961-1962
    - New York Public Library, New York, N.Y., 1953-1954
    - New York Review of Books, 1963-1966, (5 folders)
    - New York Times, 1953-1957, (2 folders)
    - Newsweek, 1957-1962, (2 folders)